Claire Sparrow-Clarke



cmsparrow18@gmail.com



(403) 892-9829

Summary

I'm a self-taught front-end developer with a background in musicology and violin performance. I've completed courses from SheCodes and Codecademy, and have experience with many technologies including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Qwik, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, and most recently I'm learning TypeScript.

My background as a musician has taught me valuable skills that transfer over to the tech industry, such as perfectionism, collaboration, discipline, problem-solving, resilience, and a growth mindset. I'm committed to delivering quality work and continually learning.

Experience



Web Development Intern

Miyar

Apr 2023 - Present (6 months)

As a web developer at Miyar, I help create and maintain the marketing website built in WordPress fullsite-editor and the customer dashboard using Qwik, Tailwind CSS and TypeScript.

Violinist

Brampton Rose Orchestra

Sep 2022 - May 2023 (9 months)

I played as a section first violinist, learning repertoire to a professional level for rehearsals and concerts.

Violin and Piano Instructor

self employed

Sep 2022 - Present (1 year 1 month)

I have been teaching violin and piano privately out of my home studio and over zoom. I incorporate technique, theory, history and creativity/musicality to help my students have fun and grow into wellrounded musicians with a solid foundation.

Violin and Piano Instructor

Ontario's Professional School of Music

Jul 2022 - Sep 2022 (3 months)

Taught a handful of piano and violin students in the school approved method and curriculum.



🔪 Usher

University of Victoria

Oct 2020 - May 2021 (8 months)

Was responsible for sanitizing the recital hall before and after concerts, made sure staff and students adhered to university COVID-19 safety protocol.



Violinist: Regina Chamber Strings

Stirling Bridge International Arts Festival

Jul 2018 - Jul 2018 (1 month)

I was invited to join the Regina Chamber Strings as they attended the Stirling Bridge International Arts Festival in Scotland. We toured and gave performances in several cities, along with groups from Germany and the United States.

Violinist

Lethbridge Symphony

Mar 2016 - Mar 2018 (2 years 1 month)

Learned repertoire for and played in several concerts from the end of the 2016 season to the end of the 2018 season. Attended sectionals and weekly rehearsals, and played in both the second violin and the first violin sections over the years.

Education



University of Victoria

Bachelor of Music-BMus, Musicology and Sound Studies, minor in Anthropology 2018 - 2022

Tafelmusik Baroque Summer Institute

Attended the summer institute, Baroque performance

May 2022 - Jun 2022

Attended daily lectures and group lessons in Baroque style, music history and performance practice.

Licenses & Certifications

Advanced React Development - SheCodes

db8643e906080886e40ec20e4b5ace7a

Advanced Web Development - SheCodes

490fd5a5311c435a8552fd70cea27c07

Advanced Responsive Web Development - SheCodes

63e72a2c602c0893575f39f3157ebf91

Introduction to Web Development - SheCodes

39097afa5767bace58171abbf46a4e18

React Development - SheCodes

847a24ea8462e70dfd7dd3d1954b6a0f

Learn CSS: Responsive Design Course - Codecademy 62EFFD4C48

- Learn Navigation Design Course Codecademy 62F1418748
- Learn Bootstrap Codecademy 62F5A3A8C1
- Front-End Developer SheCodes
- Introduction to Coding SheCodes 28a606fd57f5468fd67054dff9fd1caa
- Web Development SheCodes db5b86c9fa5f40b1d4061bf9078e0ab9
- Responsive Web Development SheCodes 142ef612720be292ca2b2abb8a0a6e5e
- Advanced React Development SheCodes db8643e906080886e40ec20e4b5ace7a

Skills

Music Performance • Research • JavaScript • CSS • HTML • Orchestral Music • Violin • Ushering • Chamber Music • Youth Mentoring

Honors & Awards

- Erich Schwandt Undergraduate Scholarship in Music University of Victoria Mar 2022
 Scholarship
- Joseph Patrick Cunningham Memorial Scholarship University of Victoria Mar 2022
 Scholarship
- Longton Scholarship University of Victoria
 Jul 2021
 Scholarship
- Herbert and Eva Schaefer String Scholarship University of Victoria
 Aug 2020
 Scholarship

Mary M. & Erich P. Schwandt Scholarship - University of Victoria Aug 2020 Scholarship

Dr. John S. Willis Memorial Scholarship - University of Victoria
Aug 2019
Scholarship

Betty Dewick Scholarship in Music - University of Victoria
Feb 2019
Scholarship

University of Victoria Entrance Scholarship - University of Victoria
Aug 2018
Scholarship

Daisie Thirlwall Scholarship in Violin - University of Victoria
Jul 2018
Scholarship

Adaskin Endowment for Strings - University of Victoria
Jul 2018
Scholarship